자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
저기요
지금 두 시인데요
Excuse me.
It's 2 o'clock.
- 박사님께서 조금 늦으시네요
- 알겠어요, 괜찮습니다
- The doctor's just running a little late.
- Okay. No problem.
얼마나 늦으실 건지
말씀해 주셨나요?
How late is he running?
Did he say?
몇 분이면 될 거예요
오래 걸리지 않을 거예요
Just a few minutes.
It won't be long.
저기, 제가 여기 있는 걸
알고 계실까요?
Listen, does he,
does he know I'm here?
잠깐 들어가서 얘기하는 게
좋을 것 같은데요
Maybe I could just pop in
and tell him.
그다지 좋은 생각은
아닌 것 같네요 / 그렇죠
I don't think that's such
a good idea, Mr. Monk. / No.
- 나탈리는 어디 있어요?
- 밖에 있어요
- Where's Natalie?
- She's out.
심부름을 좀 시켰거든요
She's running some errands.
나탈리에게 전화해 보시겠어요?
Would you like to call her?
어서 전화해 보시죠
Let's call her.
- 여보세요, 몽크 씨
- 나탈리, 저예요
- Hello, Mr. Monk.
- Natalie, it's me.
에이드리안...
알죠? 몽크요
Adrian, you know, Monk.
- 알아요, 몽크 씨
- 박사님이 좀 늦으시네요
- Yes, Mr. Monk, I know.
- Dr. Kroger is running late.
그럼 나한테 할 말이 있겠군요, 그렇죠?
Then you'll have something
to talk about, won't you?
제가 거기로 갈까요?
5분 거리에 있는데
Do you need me to come over?
I'm five minutes away.
어딘데요?
Where are you?
잘 모르겠어요
그냥 커피숍에 있어요
I don't even know.
I'm at some coffee shop.
- 제가 말한 칫솔 찾았어요?
- 그럼요
- Did you find that toothbrush?
- Yes, sir.
약국을 다섯 군데나 돌아다녀야
했지만 아무튼 찾았어요
Had to go to about five
drugstores, but I found it.
거틀러 4000이에요
The Gertler 4000
고연성 폴리우레탄 모 맞죠?
with the extra-soft polyurethane bristles?
네, 파란색 고무 손잡이가 달린 거요
Yes, and the blue rubber handle.
Yes, sir.
다행이네요
Thank god.
- 트루디 사진은요?
- 방금 사진관에서 왔어요
- What about Trudy's picture?
- I just came from the frame shop.
- 그것도 갖고 왔어요
- 어때요?
- I got that too.
- Well, how does it look?
정말 잘해 놨어요
흠집 하나 찾을 수 없네요
You know, they did a really good job.
You can't even see that scratch.
- 아주 훌륭해요
- 정말 예뻤네요
Excellent. / She really was pretty.
네, 그랬죠
Yes, she was.
정말 괜찮아요?
제가 거기로 가도 되는데요
Are you sure you're okay?
Maybe I should just come over.
아뇨, 아뇨
난 괜찮아요
No. No, no.
You know what, I'm okay.
솔직히 말하자면, 괜찮을 거예요
In fact, I'm gonna be fine.
알았어요, 그럼
상담 잘하세요
Okay, well, have a good session.
끝나면 거기로 갈게요
I'll be there when you get out.
고마워요
Thank you.
트루디?
Trudy?
트루디, 트루디?
Trudy, Trudy?
잘 지내시죠, 재크?
Hi, how are you, Zach?
정말 반가워요
How nice to see you.
늦어서 죄송해요
Sorry I'm a little late.
MONK Season 4 Epi. 6
Mr. Monk and Mrs. Monk
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
영문대본
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
김웅식(lx403dm@nate.com)
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
안은정(actwo@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/08/12
에이드리안, 기다리게 해서 미안해요
Adian, I'm sorry to have
kept you waiting.
매기가 말하길 밖에서
약간 걱정했다면서요
Maggie said that you were getting
a little anxious out there.
맞아요, 약간 흥분됐거든요
Oh, that's true.
I'm pretty excited.
- 몇 가지 소식이 있어요
- 그래요?
- I have some news.
- Really?
아시다시피, 어제는
트루디의 생일이었죠
As you know, yesterday
was Trudy's birthday.
전 묘지로 갔죠
I went to the grave.
그리고 집으로 돌아와
아내의 시 몇 개를 다시 읽었는데
Then I came home and
I re-read some of her poems.
절 사로잡는 구절이
하나 있었어요
There was this one passage
that really got to me.
전 계속 반복해서 읽었어요
I, I, I, I just kept
re-reading it.
그 싯구는
It goes,
"녹아내리는 눈은
신의 눈물 같다"
"The snows that burn away,
like tears of god,"
"새로운 세상을 드러내자"
"reveal the world anew."
"우린 새롭게 태어났다"
"We are reborn."
"영원히 잃어버리는 것은 없다"
"Nothing is lost forever."
- 아름답네요
- 그렇죠
That's beautiful. / Yes.
정말 영원히 잃어버리는 것은 없죠
I mean, nothing is lost forever.
아내가 나에게 말하는 것 같았어요
It was as if she was speaking to me.
마치 아내가 말하길
내가 자기 없이 남아있는 건...
Like she was saying,
I'm here without her...
이유가 있다고요
for a reason.
제 생각엔...
I think...
제 생각엔 아내가 저보고
새 인생을 살라고 하는 거 같아요
I think she wants me to let go.
와우
Wow.
정말 놀랍죠?
와우!
I know. Wow!
게다가 어제는 라디오에서
노래를 듣고 있는데...
And then yesterday,
the radio was playing a song.
하지만 그건 라디오가 아니었어요
But it wasn't the radio.
라디오가 아니었다고요?
It wasn't the radio?
키스해 보고픈 아가씨들이 있네
There are chicks
just right for some kissing
난 몇 명과 키스하게 될 거야
and I mean to kiss me a few
그게 뭐였는지 아세요?
You know what it was?
저였어요
It was me.
저였다고요
제가 노래를 부르고 있었어요
It was me. I was singing.
제가 행복한 것 같아요
I think I'm happy.
- 그게 가능해요?
- 왜 안 돼요?
- Is that possible?
- Why not?
너무 늦어서 문제죠
It's so long overdue.
행복해요! / 그럼요!
Happy! / Yes!
- 난 행복하다고요
- 그럼, 그럼요
- I'm happy.
- Yes, yes.
그리고 오늘 아침
위를 쳐다보다가
Then this morning, I looked up.
벽에 걸린 그림이
약간 기울어진 걸 봤지만
There was a picture on the wall,
it was a little crooked.
전 계속 식사를 했어요
I just kept eating.
일어나서 바로잡지 않았다고요
I didn't get up and fix it.
뭔가 알아채긴 했죠
유리잔이 테이블 위에 있는데
I know because the glass
here on the table,
아직까지도 받침대 위에
되돌려놓지 않고 있잖아요
you still haven't put it back
on the coaster.
- 어떻게 생각하세요?
- What do you think?
제가 그런 질문을 할 때마다
박사님은 항상 똑같이 반문하시네요
Every time I say, "what do you think?",
You say, "what do you think?".
아무튼 어떻게 생각하시냐고요?
Well, what do you think?
함부로 말하긴 그렇지만
I'm almost afraid to say it.
아무래도 나아지고 있는 것 같아요
I think I might be getting better.
에이드리안, 시를 읽거나
몽크가 보였던 반응들을
Adrian, reading the poem,
the reaction you had to it,
식역 현상이라 합니다
(식역:감지할 수 있는 지각의 경계점)
it's what we call a threshold event.
그건 아주 큰 첫걸음이에요
It's a big first step.
첫걸음이 가장 어려운 거죠
First steps are the hardest.
- 괜찮으세요?
- 네, 네, 그냥...
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, yeah, just, um...
너무나 오랫동안
기다려온 일이라서요
it's been, like, such a long time
that I've been waiting.
아, 고마워요
Oh, thank you.
미안합니다
I'm sorry.
눈물을 보여서 미안합니다
I'm sorry, I'm crying.
미안해요, 미안해요
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- 제 행동 때문에 불편하신가요?
- 네, 불편해요
- This doesn't make you uncomfortable?
- Yes, it does.
당연한 거 아닌가요?
But what doesn't?
누군가에게 저에 대해
말씀하신 적 있나요?
Did you tell anybody about me?
종업원이 어딨지?
갑자기 안 보이네
Where's our waitress?
She just disappeared.
재크...
엘링하우스 씨
Zach, Mr. Ellinghouse,
이건 아주 중요한 거예요
누군가에게 저에 대해 말씀하셨나요?
this is very important.
Did you tell anybody else about me?
누구에게 말할까?
제니스가 죽었는데...
Who would I tell?
Janice is gone.
나에겐 걔 하나뿐이었다고
She's all I had.
난 이런 스파이 짓이 싫어, 트루디
I don't like this cloak
and dagger stuff, Trudy.
절 믿으세요
다 당신을 위한 거니까요
Well, believe me,
it's for your own good.
기억나요? 절 트루디라고
부르지 마시라고 했잖아요
Remember, I asked you
not to call me Trudy.
리사라 부르세요
Call me Lisa.
아, 맞다
미안해, 리사
Oh, yeah, I'm sorry, Lisa.
난 아직도 자네가 왜 자기의
죽음을 꾸며냈는지 이해가 안 가
I still don't understand
why you had to fake your own death.
가족을 보호하기 위해서였어요
I was protecting my family.
전 항만 지역의 과격파 단체에
관한 기사를 쓰고 있었는데
I was writing an article about
an extremist group in the bay area.
그들이 절 찾기 시작했고
And they were looking for me.
절 찾게되면 남편까지
죽일 게 뻔했거든요
They would've killed me and my husband
for sure if they'd had found me.
그걸 막는 방법은 죽음을
위장하는 것뿐이었어요
The only way to stop them
was to pretend I was dead. / Whoa.
자, 참치 샌드위치와 커피 한 잔
그리고 계피쪽입니다
Here we go. Tuna fish sandwich and
a coffee and one cinnamon stick.
- 계피쪽?
- 네, 설탕 대신이죠
- Cinnamon stick?
- Yeah, to sweeten it.
마드리드에서 배운 작은 지혜죠
It's a little trick
I picked up in Madrid.
아, 맞다. 자네와 재니스는
마드리드에 갔었지
Oh, that's right.
You and Janice went to Madrid.
걔가 썼던 편지를
전부 보관하고 있다네
I have all the letters she wrote.
I kept everything.
알고 있어요
I know you did.
그래서 제가 여기 온 거예요, 재크 씨
That's why I'm here, Zach.
이야, 좋은 샌드위치군
셀러리 조각을 넣었네
Hey, great sandwich.
They got little pieces of celery in it.
좀 줄까?
You want some?
아뇨, 못 먹어요
생선 알레르기가 있어요
No, I can't.
I'm allergic to fish.
아, 맞다
기억나는군
Oh, that's right,I remember.
난 모든 걸 다 기억하고 있다네
I remember everything.
바로 생각이 안 날 뿐이야
Eventually.
얘기 좀 해요, 재크 씨
We need to talk, Zach.
제니스가 남긴 열쇠 말이에요
가지고 계시죠?
About the key, the key
that Janice left you. Do you have it?
아직도 걔가 죽었다는 게 믿기지 않아
Oh, I still can't believe she's gone.
알죠, 알아요
가슴 아픈 일이에요
I know, I know. It hurts.
저도 제니스가 그리워요
I miss her too.
이건, 이건 아주 중요한 거예요
This is, this is very important.
열쇠를 갖고 계세요?
Do you have the key?
찾아 봤지만 못 찾겠더라고
I looked for it.
I couldn't find it.
오늘 밤에 찾아볼 건데
꼭 찾아낼게. 약속하지
I'll look for it tonight.
I pro, I'll find it. I promise.
좋아요
Okay.
내일 킵 가에 있는
도서관 앞에서 만나요
I'll meet you on Keep street
in front of the library tomorrow.
- 어딘지 아시죠?
- 그럼
- Do you know where that is?
- Yeah.
10시에요 / 10시
10 o'clock. / 10.
절 실망시키지 마세요
Zach, don't let me down.
그건 제 열쇠예요
It's my key.
제니스는 제가 갖길 원했어요
Janice wanted me to have it.
맛볼 준비가 되어 있는 와인이 있네
There is wine all ready for tasting
마요네즈 조금
A little mayonnaise.
약간의 레몬즙
Some lemon juice.
소금 조금, 아주 조금
흩뿌리면 돼요
A little salt, just a pinch.
Just a sprinkle.
- 케빈, 정말 고마워요
- 그런 말 마세요
- Oh, Kevin, I really appreciate this.
- Oh, stop.
이웃이 왜 있겠어요
This is what neighbors are for.
이거면 충분할까요?
사람들이 얼마나 오죠?
Is that enough?
How many people are coming?
몰라요
I don't know.
경감님이 매년
바비큐 파티를 했지만
The captain has this barbecue every year,
but I never felt like going before.
내가 가고 싶어했던 적은 없거든요
어, 그럼 이번 파티는
사교 무대에 데뷔하는 셈이네요?
Oh, so this is like
your coming-out party?
내 생각엔...
I think I...
나탈리, 괜찮아요?
Natalie, are you okay?
네, 그냥 좀 피곤해서요
Yeah, I'm just tired. / Yeah.
자, 공식적으로
Okay, for the record,
이건 약간 좌우가 안 맞지만
난 상관 안 해요
this one is a little uneven,
but I don't care.
- 그래도 쓸 거예요
- 좋아요
- I'm gonna use it anyway.
- Okay.
예전의 나라면 집착했겠지만...
잠시만요
The old me would've obsessed
with making it, hold on.
- 자, 하지만 그냥 넘어갈 거예요
- 그냥 넣는 거죠
- Okay, but now I'm gonna let it go.
- Letting it go.
넣을 거예요
Letting it go.
들어갔네요
It's gone.
- 잠시만요
- 좋아요
- One second.
- All right.
- 몽크 씨?
- 네?
- Mr. Monk?
- Yeah?
오늘 줄리의 의사와 얘기했는데
생선 알레르기가 있을 수도 있대요
I spoke with Julie's doctor today.
He said she might be allergic to fish.
- 저런, 불쌍한 녀석
- 그러게요
- Oh, poor kid.
- Yeah.
생선 알레르기가 있는
사람이 또 있어요?
Do you know anybody else
who's allergic to fish?
제 여동생네 길 건너에 사는 남자가
I think the man who lives
across the street from my sister
생선 알레르기인 것 같아요
is allergic to fish.
정확히 길 건너는 아니고
Not right across the street.
사실은 뭐랄까...
Actually, you know what?
길이라 하긴 뭐하고
거의 막다른 골목 구조죠
It's not even really a street.
- It's more of a cul-de-sac.
- That's great, Kevin.
알았어요, 케빈
몽크 씨는요?
How about you, Mr. Monk?
없어요
No.
아, 트루디가 그랬었죠
Well, Trudy was.
아, 제가 가장 좋은 소식을
말 안 했군요
Oh, I didn't tell you the best part.
Here's the best part.
크로거 박사님이 경찰청에 전화해서
제 복권을 추천해 주실 거예요
Dr. Kroger is gonnna call the department
and recommend me for reinstatement.
그거, 그거...
축하해요
That's, that is...
congratulations.
저기, 혹시
Hey, I know.
나중에 내 옛날 유니폼이
아직 맞는지 보자고요
Later, let's get my old uniform down
and see if it fits.
한 말씀 드리자면
I'll tell you something.
이거 많이 먹으면
절대 안 맞을 거예요
It's not gonna fit if you eat
too much of this.
절대로 안 맞을 거예요
It's never gonna fit.
저기, 몽크 씨를 안다는
어떤 사람을 만났어요
Hey, I met somebody.
He said he knew you.
- 재크 엘링하우스라고 알아요?
- 엘링하우스요?
- Zach Ellinghouse?
- Ellinghouse?
네
Right.
그 사람 딸이 트루디와 일했었는데
Trudy used to work with his daughter.
잘 지내신대요?
How's he doing?
- 잘 지낸대요
- 잘됐군요
- He's fine.
- Good.
- 몽크 씨?
- 네?
Mr. Monk? / Yeah?
- 꼭 해야할 말이 있어요
- 해보세요
- There's something I have to tell you.
- Okay.
정말 맛있는 감자 샐러드네요
That's good potato salad.
안 갖고 계시다니
무슨 말이에요?
What do you mean you don't have it?
- 약속한 걸로 아는데요
- 트루디, 화내지 마
- I thought we had a deal.
- Trudy, don't get mad.
난 그냥 약간의 보상이
필요하다는 거야
I'm just talking about some compensation.
그 열쇠가 뭐에 필요한 건지 모르지만
I don't know where that key goes.
Maybe it's to something really valuable.
그걸로 아주 값나가는 물건을
찾으려는 거 아냐?
아뇨, 값나가는 거 아니에요, 재크
말씀드렸잖아요, 그건...
No, no, it's not valuable, Zach.
I told you. It...
그냥 제니스와 제가 했던
조사 자료를 찾으려는 거예요
it's just some research
that Janice and I did together.
아셨어요? 그냥 종이들이라고요
Okay? It's just some old papers.
정말 열쇠를 갖고 싶어하는군
You're really anxious about it.
알다시피 난 청구서 같이
돈 쓸 데가 있어
I have expenses, you know.
Like bills.
제니스는 도와줄 수 없으니
Janice isn't here to help me.
누가 날 도와주겠어?
Who's gonna help me?
알았어요, 돈이 필요하시군요
Okay, you want some money.
얼마나 필요한지 말하세요
So tell me how much.
Give me a number.
1,000달러
그리 많은 액수는 아니지
$1,000, that's not too much.
좋아요, 오늘 드리죠
Fine. I'll have it today.
3시에 댁으로 가겠어요
I'll be at your house at 3 o'clock.
재크 씨, 전 그 열쇠 없이
절대 안 떠날 거예요
And Zach, I am not leaving
without that key.
무슨 짓이죠?
What are you doing?
누구시죠?
Who are you?
나탈리 티거예요
Natalie Teeger.
난 당신의...
I work for your...
난 에이드리안을 위해 일해요
I work for Adrian.
- 카메라 주세요
- 무슨 일인지 제발 말해줘요
- I need that camera.
- Just please tell me what's going on.
에이드리안에게 말했어요?
Have you told Adrian about me?
하지 마세요
Don't.
그럴 수 없을 거예요
You can't.
그이를 정말 위한다면
말 못할 거예요
If you care about him at all,
you can't tell him.
이 일을 알면 몽크가 엉망이
될 거란 거 알잖아요
We both know this would kill him.
난 죽은 거예요
I'm dead.
난 그렇게 있어야 해요
I have to stay that way.
아셨죠?
Understand?
다 된 거 같군
Okay.
- 저건 어때?
- 저거요?
- How about that one?
- That one?
그래 / 저거는...
Yeah. / That one.
- 저건 뭐가 잘못됐는데?
- 균형이 안 맞았거든요
- Now, what was wrong with that one?
- Oh, that was lopsided.
자, 자넨 빵을 맡아
Here, you do the buns.
바꾸자
Switch.
저기요, 잘 익은 걸로 주세요
Hey, guys. Well done, please.
잘 익은 거라...
Well done.
- 어서, 빵이 필요해
- 빵입니다
- Come on, need a bun.
- The bun.
고마워요
Thanks.
아, 그거...
Okay, that...
약간 중앙에서 벗어났어요
that's a little off-center.
제, 제가 제대로 놓아드리죠
I could, I could
reposition that for you.
그런데 말이죠
그냥 넘어가죠 뭐
Or, you know what?
I'm gonna, I'm gonna let it go.
맛있게 드세요
인생은 너무 짧잖아요
You enjoy it.
Life is too short.
그냥 넘어갑시다
Just let it go.
경찰청장님께서 자넬 조건부로
복권하는 게 어떠냐고 물으셨는데...
You know, the commissioner asked me
what I thought about bringing
you back on a contingency basis.
시도해 볼 만하다고 말씀드렸어
I told him I thought we should try it.
- 경감님...
- 아무 말도 하지마
Captain.../ No, don't say anything.
차근차근 해나가자고, 알겠지?
We'll take it one day at a time, okay?
잠시만요
Excuse me.
그리고 말이야
Well, listen.
그게...
There's a...
말했어야 했는데 하지 않은
몇 가지 얘기가 있어
there's a few things that
I should say that I don't.
그러니까 혼자서
몇 가지 생각을 해왔었다네
I mean I've been working
on a few things myself.
뭐 자네가 완벽하지
않다는 건 확실하지만...
Well, you're not perfect,
god knows, but...
자넨 여전히 내가 본
최고의 경찰일 거야
You're still probably
the best cop I've ever met.
그리고 자네와 함께 일한 건
내 생애 최고의 영광이었어
And working with you has been
one of the great honors of my life.
자넨 최고야
You're the man.
진심이라고
And I mean that.
저도 마찬가집니다, 경감님
Right back at you, sir.
사랑합니다
I love you, man.
뭐 나도 그래
Yeah, I, well, do so.
경감님이 저보고 최고래요
He said I was the man.
눈물까지 고였다니까요
He was getting all teary.
정말요? 뭐...
Really? Well...
경쟁하는 건 아니지만
1등이라는 건 좋은 거예요
Not that it's competition or anything,
it's just nice to be number one.
실례할게요
Excuse me.
어이, 폴리
비상사태야
Hy, Paulie, a red alert.
캐런에게 맥주가 거의 다
떨어졌다고 전해줘
Tell Karen that we're
almost out of beer.
경감님, 시간 있어요?
Captain, do you have a minute?
물론이죠
Sure.
좀 이상하게 들리시겠지만...
Uh, look, I know this sounds weird but...
트루디가 죽었을 때
현장에 있었나요?
were you there when Trudy died?
누구요, 트루디 몽크요?
Who, Trudy Monk?
아뇨, 한 시간 후에 도착했었죠, 왜요?
No, no, I got there an hour later. Why?
그럼 시체를 직접
확인한 건 아니네요?
So you didn't actually see the body?
뭘 알고 싶은 거예요?
What are you getting at?
오늘 아침에 그녀를 봤어요
I met her this morning.
얘기도 했고요
I talked to her.
드디어 찾았군요
Oh, finally.
여기 돈 있어요
Here's your money.
원하시면 세어보세요
You can count it if you want.
- 마음이 바뀌었어
- 무슨 소리예요?
- Changed my mind.
- What are you talking about?
약속하셨잖아요
We had a deal.
재니스는 이 열쇠를 나에게 줬어
자네에게 남기지 않았다고
My Janice gave me this key.
She didn't leave it for you.
왜 그랬다고 생각해?
Why do you think she did that?
저에게 남길 수 없었잖아요, 안 그래요?
Well she couldn't
leave it to me, could she?
왜? / 제가 죽은 줄로
알고 있었잖아요
- Why?
- She thought I was dead.
모든 기록들을 대학에
기증하기로 마음먹었어
I've decided to leave all her papers
and her notebooks to the university.
재크 씨
Zach, Zach.
그 기사는 재니스와
제가 함께 작업했어요
Janice and I worked on
that story together.
그 조사 기록들은
저희 둘의 소유란 말이에요
Those papers belong to both of us.
글쎄...
생각 좀 해봐야겠어
I don't know.
I have to think.
재크 씨, 이건 게임이 아니에요
열쇠를 주세요!
Zach, this isn't a game.
Give me the key!
- 트루디, 무슨 짓이야?
- 열쇠를 줘요, 재크
- Trudy, what are you doing?
- Give me the key, Zach.
- 저에게 주세요
- 안 돼, 트루디!
- Give it to me.
- No, Trudy! Don't!
어서 제게 주세요!
Just give it to me!
그럴 리가 없어요
It's not possible.
불가능하다고요
It's impossible.
몽크를 보호하기 위해
죽음을 가장했다고 말했어요
She said she faked her own death
to protect him.
죽기 전에 구급대원에게 말을 했어요
She talked to a paramedic
before she died.
그 사람이 거짓말을 했나 보죠
Maybe he was lying.
아니면 그 계획에 동참했거나
Or maybe he was in on it.
경감님, 전 그녀를 미행했었는데
한 남자를 만나고 있었어요
Captain, I've been following her.
She's been meeting a man.
그 나이 많은 사람 이름은
재크 엘링하우스였어요
This older guy named Zach Ellinghouse.
그 남잘 아세요?
Do you know him?
엘링하우스라, 아니요
Ellinghouse, no.
열쇠에 대해 다투고 있었어요
They've been arguing about a key.
트루디의 열쇠를
그 남자가 갖고 있다면서요
He has some key that belongs to her.
이거 얼마나 마신 거예요?
How many of those have you had?
경감님, 전 트루디 몽크를 봤어요
Captain, I saw Trudy Monk.
사진은 찍었나요?
Did you take her picture?
네, 하지만 그녀가
필름을 뺏어갔어요
Yeah, but she took the film.
경감님!
Captain!
그래, 알았어
Yeah. Okay.
미션 힐에 사건이 생겼습니다
We just caught one in Mission hill.
지금? / 이웃집에서
싸우는 걸 들었답니다
- Now?
- Neighbor heard a fight.
문이 열려있어 들어가보니
시체를 있었답니다
Door was open,
she went in, found a body.
캐런이 난리 치겠군
Karen's gonna kill me.
알았어, 필비와 디트리치를 불러
All right, grab Philby and Deitrich.
빈튼 418번지 아파트 3-D호이고
All right, 418 Vinton, apartment 3-D.
피해자 성명은 엘링하우스입니다
Victim's name was Ellinghouse.
엘링하우스요?
Ellinghouse?
네, 재크 엘링하우스입니다
왜요? 아는 사람이에요?
Yeah, Zachary Ellinghouse.
Why? You know him?
무슨 일이에요?
Hey, what's going on?
아무것도 아냐
Nothing.
출동할 겁니다
방금 미션 힐에 사건이 터졌거든요
We're rolling.
There's a fresh one in Mission hill.
- 좋아! 나도 간다
- 아니, 이봐 몽크
- All right, let's go. I'm in.
- No, hey, hey, Monk.
이 사건엔 자네가 필요 없어
Look, we don't need you on this one.
자넨 여기 있으면 좋겠네
I want you to stay here.
그래, 그릴 좀 닦아줘
Uh, clean the grill.
정말 기름이 많이 끼었어
The grill is really greasy.
그래요 / 네?
Yeah. / What?
그래요, 어서
재밌겠는데요
Yeah, yeah, come on.
It'll be fun.
무슨 소리예요?
전 복권될 거라고요!
What are you talking about?
I'm getting my badge back!
다시 팀에 합류한 거 아니에요?
I'm back on the team, right?
어서 가요
나도 갈 거라고요
Come on. Let's go. I'm in.
어서 준비해요
Let's lock and load.
여기 먼지가 많네요
It's really dusty in here.
몽크 씨, 차에서 기다리는 게 좋겠어요
Mr. Monk, maybe you should
wait in the car.
아뇨, 전 괜찮아요
No, no, no. I'm fine.
몽크, 이 사건에 대한
보수는 줄 수 없어
You know, Monk, we can't
pay you for this one.
그럼 공짜로 일 할게요
그 정도쯤이야 아무것도 아니죠
On, it's on the house.
Least I could do.
바로 여기군요
And here we go.
시체가 여기 있었어?
Body was here?
네, 책상 위로 엎드렸는데
Yeah, looks like he was
on the desk face down,
저거에 찔린 후 바닥으로
굴러 떨어진 것 같네요
and he fell on to this thing.
Rolled over onto the floor.
- 저걸 뭐라 그러죠?
- 서류꽂이
- What do you call that thing?
- Spindle.
맞다, 서류꽂이
Spindle. Damn it.
보고서를 작성해야 하거든요
Finish my report.
카펫은 이 상태였나?
The rug was like this.
네
Yeah.
넘어진 것 같군요
Looks like he tripped.
계획된 게 아니에요
Wasn't premeditated.
오, 싸움이 있었군
Oh, there was a struggle.
여자였어요
With a woman.
여자? 그걸 어떻게 알지?
A woman? How do you know that?
힐 자국이 카펫에 있어요
Heel marks in the carpet.
발이 아주 작네요
She had very small feet.
발이 작은 여자들은 많잖아요
A lot of women have small feet.
향수를 뿌렸네요
She wore perfume.
샬리마예요
Shalimar.
트루디도 같은 걸 썼었는데...
Trudy wore shalimar.
잠깐만요
Wait.
돋보기 안경이 없네요
No reading glasses.
이 책에 뭔가를
숨겨놨었던 거 같아요
I think he kept something
stashed in this book.
열쇠야
감식반이 열쇠를 발견했대?
A key. Did they find a key?
아뇨, 아무것도요
No, no. Nothing.
그것 때문에 싸웠나 본데요
Maybe they were fighting over that.
이거 보세요
Look at this.
그 여자 머그잔에
립스틱이 남았어요
It's her mug, lipstick.
오, 그래
Oh, yes.
계피네요
커피를 달게 할 때 쓰죠
Cinnamon, to sweeten the coffee.
트루디가 그랬었어요
Trudy used to do that.
이 사람이 피해자야?
Is this the victim?
- 네, 이름은 재크 엘링하우스예요
- 아, 이런
- Yeah, his name's Zach Ellinghouse.
- Oh, no.
아는 사람이에요
I knew him.
엘링하우스예요, 나탈리
Ellinghouse, Natalie.
전에 물어봤던 사람이잖아요
You were just asking me about him.
경감님, 이 사람의 딸인
재니스가 같이 일했던 사람은...
Captain, his daughter, Janice,
used to work with my...
트루디예요 / 계속 트루디를
언급하시니 이상하네요
Trudy. / It's weird you keep
mentioning Trudy.
싸움 소리를 들은
목격자가 있거든요
There was a witness
who heard a struggle.
디셔 경위
그건 내가...
Uh, lieutenant.
Let me, let me...
목격자는 피해자의 말을
확실하게 들었다
Witness distinctly heard victim say,
"무슨 짓이야, 트루디?"
"what are you doing, Trudy?"
트루디...
Trudy...
그건 트루디의 이름인데
That was Trudy's name.
- 몽크 씨, 드릴 말씀이 있어요
- 뭔데요?
Mr. Monk, there's something
I need to tell you. / Yeah?
제 남편이 혹시라도 아직 살아 있다면
전 그 사실을 듣고 싶을 거예요
If Mitch were somehow still alive,
I'd want somebody to tell me.
뭘 들어요? 뭘요?
Tell you what? What?
무슨 말이에요?
What are you talking about?
상대방은 트루디예요
It's Trudy.
그녀는...
She's not...
그녀는 죽지 않았어요, 몽크 씨
She's not dead, Mr. Monk.
트루디가요?
Trudy?
그녀를 미행했어요
I've been following her.
얘기도 했고요
I talked to her.
- 이, 이건...
- 이봐, 몽크?
- This is, I mean...
- Monk. Hey, Monk?
몽크, 나도 안 믿어져, 알겠어?
Monk, I don't believe it either, okay?
- 뭐가 뭔지 모르겠다고
- 경감님...
- We don't know what's going on.
- Captain...
아마 트루디의 DNA 샘플을
구하기만 한다면...
Maybe if we just got
a sample of her DNA...
아뇨, 아뇨!
No. No!
그렇게 하면 상황 파악이 될 거야
That way we'd know where we stand.
트루디의 DNA요?
무슨 말씀이세요?
- Trudy's DNA? What are you saying?
- Maybe we could just exhume the body.
아니면 유해를 꺼내보는 건 어때요?
뭐? 시체를 파내는 건
꿈도 안 꾸고 있다고
What? We're miles away
from exhuming anything.
당신을 보호하기 위해
죽음을 가장했다고 했어요
She said she faked
her own death to protect you.
트루디는 살아있어요, 몽크 씨
She's alive, Mr. Monk.
트루디
Trudy.
트루디!
Trudy!
트루디...
Trudy...
몽크, 정말 트루디였어?
Monk, was it her?
너무 멀리 있어
확실하지 않대요
He's not sure.
She was too far away.
차량은 확인했어?
Did you make the car?
세단이었어요
Sedan.
회색 세단이었어요
Gray sedan.
차종이 뭐였는데?
What kind of sedan?
운전자는 봤어?
Did you see the driver?
- 번호판은?
- 기억이 안 난대요
- The license number?
- He doesn't remember.
내가 할 수 있는 일은 없어?
Is there anything I can do?
제가 할 수 있는...
Is there anything I...
일은 있을까요?
I can do?
어때요?
How's he doing?
어떨 거라 생각해?
How do you think he's doing?
이처럼 속수무책이었던 적이 없어
I have never felt
more helpless in my life.
방금 검사와 얘기했습니다
Well, I just spoke to Hank Merchant
at the D.A's office.
내가 허락했었던가?
Did I authorize that?
그건 아니지만
신경 안 쓰실 거라 생각했거든요
No, sir.
I figured you wouldn't mind.
- 전 최고잖아요, 기억하시죠?
- 이런 맙소사
I'm the man, remember?
Oh, god. / Well, I've laid
everything out for him,
제가 검사한테 모든 걸 다 설명했더니
유해를 발굴할 근거가
충분하다고 생각하고 있습니다
and he thinks we have enough
to exhume the body.
명령만 내리시면 됩니다
You just have to say the word.
야, 안 돼
Look, hey, no.
우린 몽크의 허락 없인
어떤 것도 파내지 않을 거야
We're not digging anything up
without Monk's okay.
그냥 몽크에게 하루에서
이틀 정도 시간을 주자고
Look, let's just give him
a day or two, okay?
경감님
Captain.
박사님, 와주셨군요
Doctor, thank god you're here.
나탈리가 전화를 했어요
Natalie called my service.
무슨 일이죠?
What's going on?
트루디가 아직 살아있을지도
모른다는 증거가 있어요
There is some evidence to suggest
that Monk's wife Trudy may still be alive.
뭐라고요?
Excuse me?
트루디가 여태껏 자신의 죽음을
가장해왔다고 생각합니다
We think she faked her own death
and has been hiding out ever since.
또 그녀가 좀 전에 있었던 살인을
저질렀다고 확신하고 있고요
And we're pretty sure
she killed a guy earlier today.
트루디가 유력한 용의자라고요
Trudy's our primary suspect.
알겠어요. 즉 몽크가
정신 분열 증세로
All right, all right,
so he's having a psychotic break.
- 착각을 하고 있다는 거군요
- 아뇨, 착각이 아니에요
- He's delusional.
- No, he's not delusional.
현재 두 명의 목격자와
물적 증거들이 있어요
We have two eyewitnesses
and some physical evidence.
이거...
This...
큰일이군요, 실례하겠습니다
This is big. Excuse me.
크로거 박사님
Dr. Kroger.
몽크 씨, 누가 왔는지 보세요
크로거 박사님이에요
Mr. Monk, look who's here.
It's Dr. Kroger.
나탈리, 잠시 자리 좀 비켜주시겠어요
Natalie, give us a minute, please.
에이드리안
Adrian.
자요, 뭐라도 좀 마셔요
Here, you have to drink something.
뭐라도 마셨나요?
Did you drink something?
잡았어요?
You got it?
그래요
Okay.
마셔요
Drink.
그래요
Okay.
에이드리안, 당신 입으로 직접
들을 때까지 아무것도 못 믿겠네요
Adrian, I'm not going to believe anything
until I hear it from you.
트루디가 살아있나요?
Is Trudy alive?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
하지만 그게 사실이라면...
But if it's true...
진실인 게 아무것도 없다는 거예요
then nothing's true.
그게 사실이라면...
If this is true...
모든 게 거짓이란 말이에요
nothing is true.
- 왜 저한테 연락 안 했을까요?
- 글쎄요
- Why didn't she contact me?
- I don't know.
곤경에 빠졌나 보죠
I don't know. Maybe she's in trouble.
- 곤경에 빠진 거예요
- 에이드리안, 어디 가요?
- She's in trouble.
- Adrian, where are you going?
에이드리안?
Adrian?
어이, 몽크?
Hey, Monk?
- 몽크, 어디 가는 거야?
- 트루디를 찾아야 해요
- Monk, where are you going?
- I have to find her.
- 같이 갈게요
- 아뇨, 나 혼자 해야 해요
- We'll go with you.
- No, I have to do this alone.
이건 저와 제 아내의 일이에요
This is between me and my wife.
그 여자는 당신이 아냐
She's not you.
당신이 아니었어
It's not you.
안녕하세요?
Hey, how you doing?
안녕하세요
Hi.
제 아내는 저 뒤에 묻혔어요
My wife is buried back there.
여전히 죽은 상태죠
She's still dead.
제가 남겨둔 자리에
그대로 있어요
She's right where I left her.
- 그렇군요
- 전 너무나...
Okay. / I am so...
안심이 되네요
relieved.
그러니까 진심으로
아내를 사랑하긴 하지만...
I mean, I love her
with all my heart but...
누구죠?
Who is this?
- 제 남편이에요
- 부군도 분명 죽었을 거예요
This is my husband.
Oh, I'm sure he's dead too.
그리고 계속 죽어있을 겁니다
And he'll stay dead.
걱정 마세요
여긴 훌륭한 공동묘지거든요
Don't worry about that.
This is an excellent cemetery.
자기들 상태가 어떤지
다 알고 있죠
They know what they're doing.
네, 여기 있는 모두가요
아마 죽은 채로요
Yeah, everybody here.
Probably dead.
얘기 잘했습니다
Nice talking to you.
맞아요, 저기예요
That's it, there.
트루디의 책상이요?
Trudy's desk?
5년간이었죠
For five years.
이 직업을 사랑했었죠
She loved this job.
제가 한 거예요
I did that.
키스하려고 기대다
커피를 쏟아버렸었죠
I was leaning in to kiss her,
spilled some coffee.
그게 몽크 씨가 마지막으로
뭔가를 쏟은 거겠네요
I'll bet it was the last time
you spilled anything in your life.
7년 후인 1999년 1월 12일에
한 번 더 그랬어요
I spilled something seven years later,
January 12, 1999.
1월 12일요?
지진이 일어나던 동안 말씀이세요?
January 12?
You mean during the earthquake?
지진도 포함해야죠
Earthquakes count.
규칙을 정해놓은 게 아니거든요
I don't make the rules.
몽크 씨, 뭐 하나 물어도 돼요?
Mr. Monk, can I ask you something?
어제 공동묘지에서
무슨 일이 있었어요?
What happened yesterday in the cemetery?
어떻게 우리가 본 여자가
트루디가 아니란 걸 알아요?
How do you know the woman
we've been seeing isn't Trudy?
아직 문서보관소에
사본이 한두 개 있더군요
We still have one or two
copies in the archive.
가지셔도 됩니다
You can keep that one.
전 이해가 안 가요
대체 왜 트루디로 변장했을까요?
I don't understand. Why would anybody
want to impersonate Trudy?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
직원들이 트루디를
조금이라도 닮았으면 좋겠어요
I wish some of these kids would
impersonate her a little bit.
제가 본 최고의 기자였으니까요
She was the best reporter I ever knew.
여기 있네요
Here it is.
"부두 가의 긴장"
재니스 엘링스턴, 트루디 몽크 씀
"Pier pressure" by Janice Ellinghouse
and Trudy Monk.
둘이 함께 쓴
단 하나의 기사였어요
It was the only article
they ever wrote together.
정말 최고의 기사로
퓰리처상 감이었는데 말이죠
It was a hell of a piece.
It should've won a Pulitzer.
부두노동자 조합에 관한 거네요?
It was on the dockworker's union?
조합장 에드 린들리가
이 기사 때문에 기소됐죠
Ed Lindley, the union president,
was indicted because of that article.
- 아직 감옥에 있잖아요
- 그렇습니다
- He's still in jail.
- That's right.
그자는 건드릴 수 없는 자였지만
그 둘은 조사를 멈추지 않았었어요
The guy was untouchable, but
Trudy and Janice never stopped digging.
그 기사가 역사를 만들었어요
That article made history.
린들리의 오른팔인 잭 볼린저가
이것 덕분에 조합장이 됐죠
Lindley's second in command,
Jack Bollinger,
became the union president
because of this.
아직도 역임하고 있는데
꽤 깨끗하게 운영하고 있는 것 같아요
He's still there. Seems to be running
a pretty clean shop.
와, 공범자들의 이름까지 다 적어놨네요
Well, they are really naming names here.
뇌물들 좀 보세요
Look at all these payoffs.
- 이걸 어떻게 다 알았대요?
- 부지런함과 비밀 정보원 덕이죠
- How did they get all this?
- Hard work and a secret informant.
누군지는 전혀 몰라요
Deep background.
트루디는 그게 누군지
절대 말 안 해줬어요
Trudy never told me who it was.
저한테도 둘 다 그랬죠
Well, they never told me either.
재니스의 책상은 어디죠?
Where was Janice's desk?
저쪽이에요
Over there.
아직 치우지 않고 있어요
I still haven't cleaned it out yet.
작별인사를 하기가 힘들더군요
It's hard to say goodbye.
네, 그렇죠
Yes, it is.
'임대료 지불'
"Pay rent."
네, 근데요?
Yeah, so?
주택 융자금을 낸다는 건
위에 적혀 있는데
She was already paying a mortgage.
뭘 또 임대하고 있었을까요?
105달러로 뭘 임대할 수 있죠?
What could she be renting?
What can you rent for $105?
보관용 창고를 임대해 봤는데
한 달에 저 정도 했어요
I rent a storage locker.
It costs about that much per month.
사라진 열쇠
The missing key.
책에 있었던 게
그 창고 열쇠인가 봐요
The one from the book.
It could've opened a locker.
몽크 씨, 샌프란시스코엔
그런 창고가 수백 개나 돼요
Mr. Monk, there are hundreds
of storage lockers in San francisco.
어디서부터 시작해야 하죠?
Where would we even start?
저기요, 나탈리
Well, Natalie,
3번 가 13025번지의
트랜스-칼부터 시작하는 게 어떨까요
how about Trans-calmoving & storage
13025 3rd street.
네?
What?
트랜스-칼 보관소
그 보관소가 몇 시에
문을 연다고?
This storage place,
what time does it open?
8시요
8 o'clock.
같이 가줬으면 해
Gonna need you to come along with me.
왜요?
Why?
열쇠만 가져다주면
가도 좋다고 했잖아요
You said once I got you the key,
I could leave.
계획이 바뀌었어
Change of plans.
그들이 어떤 방식의
보안장치를 해놨을지 모르거든
I don't know what kind
of security they're gonna have.
제지를 당할 경우
재니스 역할을 해줬으면 좋겠어
If we're stopped, then I'm gonna
need you to pretend to be Janice.
아, 그것도 가져가
그녀도 금발이었으니까
Oh, and bring that along.
She was a blonde too.
난 이 일이 싫어요
I hate this thing.
왜? 정말 잘 어울리는데
Why? It looks pretty good on you.
다시 말하지만, 쇼에서 본
빨간 머리는 정말 끝내줬어
Then again, you look pretty good
as that redhead in that show I saw you in.
- 그 쇼 이름이 뭐였더라?
- 사람이 죽었어요
- What was it called?
- A man is dead.
그래, 알아
그리고 미안하게 됐어
Yeah. I know that.
And I am sorry.
- 정말 불행한 사고였어
- 그리고 트루디의 남편은요?
- It was a terrible accident.
- And that other guy, Trudy's husband?
그 사람 얼굴을 잊을 수가 없어요
정말 가슴 아파했다고요
I will never forget his face.
I mean, he was really hurting.
이봐, 이미 일어난 일이야
우리도 갈 길을 가야지
Look, things happen.
We're moving on.
이제 이 일은 전적으로 사느냐
죽느냐의 문제가 됐어, 알겠어?
This is all about self-preservation now.
Do you understand?
그 안에 뭐가 있든
유출이 된다면
If whatever is in that storage
locker ever gets out,
- 난 죽은 목숨이라고
- 난 못 하겠어요
- I am a dead man.
- I can't do this.
아니, 할 수 있어
Yes, you can.
잘 들어
Look, look, look.
당신은 배우야, 그렇지?
You're an actress, aren't you?
우리의 쇼는 아직 끝나지 않았어
Well, our little show is not over yet.
좋은 아침
Good morning.
무슨 일이야?
What's going on?
대책 본부를 구성하고 있습니다
We're organizing a task force.
내 사무실에?
Out of my office?
네, 그렇습니다
Yes, sir.
신경 안 쓰실 거라 생각했거든요
Well, I figured you wouldn't mind.
전 최고잖아요, 그렇죠?
I'm the man, right?
어, 그렇지
자넨 최고지
Yeah, that's right.
You're the man.
걱정 마세요, 경감님
제가 완벽하게 통제하고 있습니다
Don't worry, sir.
I am all over this one.
러드너와 하이든 경사에게
다시 조사를 맡겼는데
I've reassigned Rudner and sergeant Hyden.
지금 오고 있습니다
이건 감식반 보고서로
They're already on their way in.
The report from the lab,
아파트에 확인 가능한
지문은 없답니다
there were no identifiable
prints in the apartment.
트루디가 떠나기 전에
다 지운 것 같습니다
Trudy must've wiped everything
down before she left.
지명수배 전단
5,000장을 인쇄 중이고
I'm running off 5,000 of those.
Wanted for questioning.
상황판에 트루디의 사진을 붙여놨고
I put a photo of her up on the hot board.
그녀의 부모와 연락을
시도하고 있습니다
And I've been trying
to contact her parents.
잠깐, 누구의 부모와
연락을 시도한다고?
Wait, you've been trying
to contact whose parents?
- 트루디요, 연락할지도 모르니까요
- 안 돼, 랜디, 잠깐만
- Trudy's, in case she tries to call them.
- No, Randy,wait, wait, wait.
그리고 이걸 언론에
공개하려고 합니다
And I'm releasing that to the press.
그게 공개자료입니다
It's a press release.
아, 경찰차장에게도
연락을 취했는데 그건...
Oh, I called the deputy commissioner too,
just wanted...
경위!
Lieutenant!
여러분, 잠깐만
Excuse me, gentlemen.
랜달...
Randall...
자네가 최고라고 말했던 건...
when I said that
about you being the man...
몽크로 착각하고 한 말이야
I thought I was talking to Monk.
그랬군요
상황 파악이 되네요
Okay, well, that explains it.
- 랜디, 그렇다고 내가...
- 아닙니다, 이해합니다
Randy, it doesn't mean
that I don't... / No, I understand.
괜찮습니다
No problem.
그냥 커피나 한 잔 갖다 드릴게요
Why don't I just get you a cup of coffee?
그거 필요 없게 됐네
Won't be needing that.
- 12번이에요
- 12번요, 어떻게 알아요?
- It's number 12.
- Number 12, how do you know?
목록을 봤죠
I saw the list.
경비원이 그냥 보여주던가요?
The security guard
just showed you the list?
그렇다기보단, 그 남자가
허리를 숙일 때 슬쩍 봤어요
Not exactly, I caught a glimpse of it
as he was bending over.
왜 허리를 숙였죠?
Why was he bending over?
제 귀걸이 찾는 걸 도와주려고요
To help me look for my earring.
헉, 귀걸이를 잃어버렸네
I lost my earring.
이런 세상에
Oh, my god.
대신할 수 없는 건데
It's irreplaceable.
리사 고모가 임종시에
주신 선물이거든요
It was a gift from my aunt Lisa
on her deathbed.
아무래도 떨어뜨린 곳이...
I think it might've fallen over...
저기네요
there.
벌써 다녀갔는지도 몰라요
Maybe she's already been here.
어젯밤 내린 비로 고인 물이
손잡이에 남아있어요
Well, there's water in the handle
from the rain last night.
문을 열었다면 물이 흘렀겠죠
It would've spilled out
if she lifted the door.
들어봐요
Listen. Listen.
제가 본 차예요
That's the car I saw.
분명 그 여자예요
It's gotta be her.
그 여자예요!
It's her, it's her.
몽크 씨, 저들이 보겠어요!
뭐하세요?
Mr. Monk, they're gonna see you!
What are you doing?
- 숙여요!
- 아내가 돌아왔었어요
- Get down!
- I had her back.
한 시간 반 정도는
For an hour and a half.
아내가 살아있을지도
모른다고 생각했었죠
I thought she might be alive.
희망이 있었어요
I had hope.
희망이란 게 가장 나쁜 거란 거
알아요? / 아니에요, 몽크 씨
- Isn't hope the worst?
- No, Mr. Monk.
희망은 좋은 거예요
Hope is a good thing.
나탈리는 너무 어려요
You're very young.
저 남자 알아요
I know this guy.
전에 본 적이 있다고요
I've seen him before.
트루디와 제니스가 쓴
기사를 갖고 있죠? / 네
Do you have the article
that Trudy and Janice wrote? / Yeah.
저자예요!
That's him!
- 저자는 잭 볼린저예요
- 조합장이군요
- That's Jack Bollinger.
- The union boss.
저자가 10년 전
익명의 제보자예요
He was their anonymous source
ten years ago.
두 명이 세상을 떠나자
Now that they're both gone,
he must be panicked that
그들의 조사 자료가 공개될까 봐
겁에 질렸을 거예요
all of their research
material will be made public.
그러면 그의 오랜 친구들이
그가 밀고했단 걸 알 테니까요
And his old friends will know
that he ratted them out.
그럼 저 여잔요?
What about the woman?
그저 볼린저가 발견한
여자일 거예요
Bollinger must've just found her.
모든 게 제니스의 아버지가 열쇠를
포기하게 하기 한 사기였어요
It was a con game to trick
Janice's father into giving up that key.
저 여자는 트루디에 관한 건
어떻게 알았을까요?
I don't, how did she know
so much about Trudy?
볼린저가 가르쳤을 거예요
Bollinger must've coached her.
기사를 쓸 때 트루디와 있었으니
많은 걸 알고 있었겠죠
He spent time with Trudy
when they were writing this,
so he knew a lot about her.
경감님께 전화할게요
I'm calling the captain.
경위, 출동이다
나탈리 전화였어
Lieutenant, we're rolling.
That was Natalie.
몽크가 사건을 해결했어
보관용 창고가 있는 길가에 있대
Monk broke the case.
There at a storage locker
right up the street.
랜디?
Randy?
랜디! 가자
Randy! Let's go.
아, 죄송합니다
저한테 말씀하신 건가요?
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
We're you talking to me?
가끔 구별하기가 힘들 거든요
It's just hard to tell sometimes.
랜디...
Randy, you know how fragile Monk is.
I have to stroke him all the time.
자넨 몽크가 얼마나 연약한지 알잖아
난 항상 몽크를 달래줘야 해
하지만 자넨 그보단 강하잖아
But you're tougher than that.
자, 자네가 최고야
가자고
Come on, you're the man.
Let's go.
음, 그러니까 개나 소나
다 최고란 거군요
Well, so, everybody's the man.
아니, 자네와 몽크뿐이야
No, just you and Monk.
자네들이 내가 가진
최고들이야. 어서 가자고
You're my two men. Let's go.
우리 둘이 물에 빠지면
누구를 구하실 거죠?
If we were both drowning,
who would you save?
글쎄, 둘 다 구해야겠지
I don't know. Both of you.
아뇨, 둘 중 하나만
구할 수 있어요
No, if you could only save one of us.
아마 몽크를 구하겠지
수영을 못 하니까
Well, I'd probably save Monk
because he can't swim
그리고 자네가 수영을
잘한다는 걸 알게 되겠지
and I happen to know
you're an excellent swimmer.
제가 닻을 붙잡고 있다고 치면요?
Suppose I was holding an anchor.
- 닻을 붙잡고 있다고?
- 네, 누굴 구하실 거죠?
- You're holding an anchor?
- Uh-huh. Who would you save then?
그냥, 닻을 놓으면 안 돼?
Well, why don't you
let go of the anchor?
가보(家寶)라서 안 돼요
It's a family heirloom.
나 간다
I'm leaving.
볼린저 씨, 난 이제 가도 되죠?
Mr. Bollinger, can I go now?
시동을 걸어
Go start the car.
안 돼요, 몽크 씨
저 여자는 트루디가 아니에요
No, no. Mr. Monk, it's not Trudy.
경감님을 기다리자고요
Let's just wait for the captain.
여기 있어요
Stay here.
뭐 하는 거예요?
What the hell are you doing?
공책과 테이프들은 찾았지만
I found some notebooks and some tapes.
라벨을 붙여놓지 않았군
But they're not all labeled.
그런데 난 하나라도
빠트리면 안 되거든
And I can't afford to miss anything.
그렇다면 차선책을 써야겠어
So we are going to plan B.
볼린저 씨, 그러지 마세요!
Mr. Bollinger, you can't do that!
- 더 이상 누가 다치는 걸 원치 않아요
- 시동이나 걸어!
- I don't want anyone else getting hurt.
- Start the damn car!
트루디...
Trudy...
이자는 여기서 뭐 하는 거지?
what the hell is he doing here?
난 트루디의 남편이에요
I'm her husband.
이런 제기랄, 끝이 없군
Son of a bitch, it never ends.
저 사람이 어떻게
우릴 발견한 거지?
How, how did he find us?
누가 또 알고 있지?
Who else knows we're here?
- 이봐, 묻고 있잖아
- 당신 머리카락...
- Hey, I'm talking to you.
- Your hair...
당신 머리카락은 좀 더...
your hair was more like, like...
저기, 전...
Look, I...
몰랐어요, 네?
I didn't know, okay?
그냥 단순한 일로만 알았다고요
I thought this was just a job.
첫 번째 줄, 12번이에요!
First row, number 12!
어이, 정신 나간 놈
여자한테서 떨어져
You, freak show.
Get away from her.
안 돼요, 볼린저 씨, 하지 마요!
No, Mr. Bollinger, don't.
- 트루디, 들어봐요...
- 좋아, 그만해!
- Trudy, listen...
- Okay, that is enough!
안 돼요!
그러지 마세요!
No, no, no!
No, don't!
재 속에서 시체를 찾을 수 있을 거야!
Looks like they're gonna
find a body in the ashes here!
선택의 여지가 없어!
이자는 너무 많이 알고 있어
I have no choice!
He knows too much.
이런 젠장
Oh, god.
이봐!
Hey!
정말 미안해요
I am so sorry.
부인을 사랑했군요
You loved her.
전해줄게요
I'll tell her.
- 이거 냄새가 나는데요
- 무슨 냄새요?
- Well, I think it stinks.
- What stinks?
몽크 씨를 복권하지
않기로 결정한 거요
The department deciding
not to reinstate you.
기회조차 안 줬으면서요
They didn't even give you a chance.
그 사람들 탓이 아니에요
You can't really blame them.
그 사건 이후로
After what happened,
- 난 원상태로 돌아간 셈이니까요
- 정상으로요?
- I'm kind of back to...
- What, normal?
이것도 일종의 정상이죠
Well, it's a kind of normal.
- 아, 잠깐만요
- 왜요?
- Uh, wait a second.
- What?
저거 두 번 건드렸는데
그렇게 되면...
Uh, I touched that one twice.
I have to...
몽크 씨, 한 번도
말 안 해줬는데요
You know, Mr. Monk,
you never told me.
공동묘지에서 무슨 일이 있었어요?
What happened in the cemetery?
어떻게 그 여자가
트루디가 아닌 걸 알았죠?
How did you know that
that woman wasn't really Trudy?
묘지에 갔을 때
Well, I went to the grave,
가슴이 여전히 아프더라고요
and it still hurt.
그래서 알았죠
So I knew.
네, 저도 그 아픔을 알죠
Yeah, I know that hurt.
절대 틀리지 않죠
It's never wrong.
네, 그래요
Nope. It isn't.
당신도 그렇고요
Neither are you.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)